Moving onto the Hollywood Freeway , we have a multiple vehicle ...
multiple injury accident .
An absolute mess from Vine Street to the valley .
If you 're in it , expect a long commute .
If you 're not , seek alternate routes .
If Dan doesn 't want to do a daily rate ,
we can talk about a weekly rate .
But I 'm telling you right now , I 'm not going below a million .
I mean , think about it . I 'm risking my reputation ...
as the host of this country 's number-one ...
nationally syndicated talk show to do
a cameo in some cheap slasher flick .
I mean , why can 't these guys write me a fucking decent part ?
You know ? I lived through the fucking thing .
By the way , did you talk to Cathy about that Navy SEAL script ?
Hang on a sec .
- Hello ? - Hello ?
- Who 's this ? - Who 's this ?
- Who are you calling ? - Oh . You know what ?
I 'm sorry . I have the wrong number .
That 's okay .
Wait a minute . I know your voice .
You sound a lot like that guy on TV . Cotton Weary .
- I do , huh ? - Yeah .
I think he 's got a really sexy voice .
- Well , thank you . - Wait a minute .
You are Cotton , aren 't you ? Oh , my God .
I am talking to Cotton Weary . I can 't believe this .
You got me . Look , I 've got someone on the other line .
Can you hold on one second ? I 'll be right back , I promise .
Yeah .
- Okay . - Yeah .
Andrea , I got to call you back . Someone 's on the other line .
So , you a big 100 % Cotton fan ?
Yeah . One hundred and ten percent .
That 's very good .
So , why don 't you tell me who you are ?
Ooh . You 're a naughty boy , Cotton .
Now , what would your girlfriend say ?
What makes you think I have a girlfriend ?
I know you do .
I 'm right outside her bathroom door .
Who is this ?
She 's in the shower . She 's got a nice little voice .
Let 's come in for a closer look .
She 's very pretty , Cotton .
A step up from Maureen Prescott .
Speaking of which , let 's play a little game .
Answer right , your girlfriend lives .
Answer wrong , she dies .
Where 's Maureen 's daughter , Sidney ?
Who the fuck is this ?
Somebody who 'd kill to know where Sidney Prescott is .
One chance , Cotton . You 've got connections . Where is she ?
You listen to me , you fucking psycho .
You lay a finger on Christine ...
and I swear to God I 'll kill you .
Wrong answer .
No . Wait . Hello ? Shit .
- Hey . - Get out of the way .
- You just hit me . - Move .
Christine , if you 're there , pick up the phone .
Christine , pick up the phone . Oh , shit .
You have reached 911 . Due to the volume of calls ...
Someone pick up the goddamn phone . Move out of the way .
Shit . Shit .
Cotton , is that you ?
Cotton ?
Honey ?
Okay , Cotton .
You know I don 't like your Stab games .
- Who is it ? Who 's there ? - Christine ?
Hon , you all right ?
I 'm home .
Jesus . You scared the shit out of me .
You 're not going to believe what just happened to me .
What are you talking about ?
- Get the hell out of here . - Okay . Okay , I 'm sorry , babe .
I didn 't mean to scare you that bad .
It 's me . Come on , open the door .
- What are you doing ? - What ?
What the fuck are you doing ?
I was ... I was just , you know , trying
to take the game to the next level .
I 'm sorry . Come on , open the door , Chris .
The game ?
- Yeah , the game . - What are you talking about ?
I 'm talking about how much fun it 's
going to be to rip your insides out .
Now , open the fucking door , Christine .
Oh , my God .
Now you 're fucking history , baby .
Christine ?
Hon ?
The recent epidemic of road rage in Los Angeles .
Innocent commuters mercilessly terrorised , even killed ...
Chris ?
- By these madmen of the freeway . - Don 't mess around , okay ?
We 're going to make them confront their
victims face-to-face , mano a mano ...
right here on 100 % Cotton .
There is carnage on our streets . And
remember , it could happen to you .
Tomorrow on 100 % Cotton . Road rage .
L.A. drivers fight back .
The news is next on channel six with our
exclusive entertainment report live ...
from tonight 's celebrity premiere in Hollywood ...
followed by ...
Oh , shit .
Chris ?
Is that you , babe ?
Chris , if you 're in there , open the door . Okay , honey ?
Chris ? Come on , baby . Open the door .
Chris . Whoa , whoa , whoa . Jesus .
It 's me , Chris . What are you doing ?
Stay back .
- Chris , what 's going on , babe ? - You 've gone crazy . That 's what .
Chris , was somebody in the house ?
No . Get back .
Okay , okay , okay . Just calm down , okay ?
- Why do you want to kill me ? - What are you talking about ?
Why do you wanna kill me ?
Gimme the club . All right , honey ? Gimme the club .
Gimme the club , please .
Christine , get out of the way .
Behind you .
Shit .
It was a simple game , Cotton . You
should 've told me where Sidney was .
Now , you lose .
Come on .
Come on , Cherokee . Come on .
Come on , Cherokee .
California Women 's Crisis Counselling .
Hey , it 's Laura from Monterrey reporting
to work . Can you patch me in ?
- Sure . Thanks , Laura . - Thank you .
California Women 's Crisis Counselling . How can I help you ?
Hi . Do I have to say my name ?
No , you don 't have to say anything you don 't want to say .
How can I help ?
I 'm 18 years old , and I have a boyfriend .
- Sometimes he hits me . - It 's okay .
- You can talk to me , all right ? - Thanks .
So , in closing , as the future journalists of America ...
there is one thing that you need to remember .
Being the best means being willing to do what the others would not .
Break the rules . Stop at nothing .
Be willing to have the world hate you ,
because that is the only way ...
that you 'll get the story , the facts and the fame .
Thank you .
- Excuse me . Excuse me . - Yes ?
So you 're saying that we should be ready to go out ...
and cut each other 's throats because that 's what you did .
- Metaphorically , yes . - Well , tell me , Miss Weathers .
- Was it worth it ? - I 'm so sorry . We 're out of time .
Gale Weathers , anchor woman for Total Entertainment .
Thank you very much .
There is a young man outside who wants to see you .
- He says he 's with the police . - The police ?
- Detective Mark Kincaid , L.A.P.D. - Hello .
That 's quite an impressive resume .
Thank you .
I assume you 're not here for an autograph .
I 'm here because Cotton Weary 's been murdered .
- Someone killed Cotton ? - And his girlfriend .
Someone who left something he wanted us to see .
I 'll show you this because you 're the
Woodsboro authority and because you knew him .
But I promise you , if you share this with
the world , it 's you I 'll be arresting .
I swear on my Pulitzer Prize , which
I plan to win one day , Detective .
This was left on Cotton Weary 's body . You
have any idea who the girl might be ?
Oh , my God .
This is Maureen Prescott . This is Sidney Prescott 's mother .
Hollywood is reeling today from news ...
of the murder of controversial talk show host Cotton Weary .
Weary had only recently finished shooting a cameo as himself ...
in the film Stab 3 , Return to Woodsboro ...
the third and final part of the famous horror series ...
based on the Woodsboro and Windsor College murders .
Before his rise to television fame ,
Cotton had been imprisoned ...
and was later exonerated for the murder
of Maureen Prescott , his former lover ...
Just yesterday , Cotton Weary was
shooting here at Sunrise Studios ...
his first cameo in a feature film , Stab 3 .
Security here is tight , but we 'll see
if we can get a statement . Excuse me .
Always a controversial man ...
Channel Eight news . We got to get in . We got to get in .
No press beyond this point .
Alone at night he crosses flames
Ashe makes a fist with his red right hand
Look , you 're worried about the movie ,
then protect the movie , okay ?
Hire more security . Hire the National
Guard . Just don 't kill the movie .
Violence in cinema is a big deal right now , Roman .
This is not the kind of news this studio is after .
So if we stop making scary movies , what ?
All the psychos in the world will retire ? Come on .
I 've been making horror movies for 30
years , never had a psycho problem .
He was your goddamn idea , guys . All right ?
An ex-con with a trashy talk show ? He
must 've pissed people off every day .
Detectives , there 's no reason to presume that Cotton 's death ...
had anything to do with this movie , is there ?
He was making a movie called Stab . He was stabbed .
Probably some psycho fan pissed off they killed Randy in Stab 2 .
Well , Tyson , that 'd make you next , wouldn 't it ?
I am not a Randy substitute . I 'm my own character .
Named Ricky , who works at the video store .
It 's an homage .
Hey . What if the killer 's Sidney Prescott ?
I mean , what the hell ever happened to
her ? She 's probably off in the woods ...
living like the fucking Unabomber , man .
I 'm starting to see why Tori Spelling and
David Schwimmer didn 't want to come back .
Guys , this was about Cotton . We are not in any danger .
" We are not in any danger , " says Candy , page 15 .
I don 't see you leaving .
You think serious black actors my age can just throw away jobs ?
It 's all a business now . They got Usher doing Pinter off-Broadway .
L.L. Cool J 's Shakespearing in the park .
- Yeah . - Maybe it 's not meant to be .
Not meant to be ? You win that talent search for the new Sidney .
50,000 girls and they pick you . You got
to be praying this movie keeps going .
Of course I am , but not at the expense of people 's lives .
Oh . Cue the violins , right ?
Jesus .
Deja voodoo .
We need this area cleared , please . Clear it .
- Gale Weathers . Oh , my God . - Shit .
I ... Listen , I know we 've never met ...
and I don 't mind you never returning
my calls , but I have to tell you ...
after two films , I feel like I am in your mind .
Well , that would explain my constant headaches .
You know , I 'm sorry things didn 't work out on 60 Minutes II .
But Total Entertainment , that 's a pretty good fallback .
Thank you .
I 'm sorry that things didn 't work out with Brad Pitt ...
but being single , that 's a pretty good fallback .
Gives me more time for my work .
After all , Gale Weathers , you 're such a complex character .
Oh , and to be played by an actress with such depth and range .
Jennifer , Nick said you wanted to ...
Gale .
Dewey .
Well , surprise , surprise . Someone dies and Gale comes running .
Gale , I think you 'll really appreciate
my character work in this one .
Someone 's helped me understand the real you .
Someone ?
Your ruthless ambition , your private self-loathing ...
and that lost and lonely little girl inside .
Lost and lonely what ?
You heard me . Thanks , Dewey , I 'll return it .
Little girl inside .
I thought you were supposed to be in Woodsboro .
Well , I 'm surprised you thought about me at all .
Listen , I got to get back to work . I really don 't have time for this .
- Wait a minute . You work here ? - Yeah .
The movie needed a technical advisor .
Someone who went through the real experience , knew the real people .
- Hey , Dewey . - Hey , Tom .
Hey . It 's the real Gale Weathers .
Real from top to bottom .
Tom Prinze . Watch your show all the time .
You 're so right . Pop culture is the politics of the 21st century .
- Thank you . - And that story that you did ...
last month on me crashing my car ?
Wow , was that ever powerful journalism .
Right ...
I especially liked the way you implied
that it was caused by drinking and drugs .
And that the tyre blowout was faked . That was great .
Tom , sometimes in journalism you have to ...
Are you parked in the lot ? Because I should check to make sure ...
that nobody 's messed with your brake line .
Who 's he supposed to be ?
He 's playing you ? Him ?
What ?
I did not come here to fight with you , Dewey .
- Cotton 's killer left a picture . - Of Sid 's mum .
- The detectives told me . - Well , does Sidney know about it ?
Listen , Sidney doesn 't need you and your camera in her life .
Do you see a camera ?
Right . You bought me this purse , didn 't you ?
- Yeah . - Look , it 's a habit .
I walk out of the house , I turn it on .
What the hell is this ?
- It 's like perfume . - Gale Weathers ?
- Could I be more popular ? - No press .
Mo press on set . Get that woman out of here .
Yes , Mr Milton . Let 's go .
Wait a minute . Wait a minute . Where is Detective Kincaid ?
I am working with Kincaid , Dewey .
Come on . Move along , miss . Let 's go .
Rules are rules , Gale . But , really , it was great seeing you .
Stab 3 is a closed set . But just up
ahead is the old Seinfeld stage .
Now , does anybody need a potty break ?
- Oh , I do . - Yeah , me too .
Okay , let go . Thanks for your help , boys .
Holy shit , Silent Bob . It 's that TV .
News chick , Connie fucking-Chung .
Hey , Connie , how 's Maury ?
Dude , I think she likes me . See how she 's looking at me ?
It 's happening again .
Cotton had a lot of enemies , Sid .
The police aren 't saying it 's related to us .
Do you ever think about her ?
Your mum ?
None of this would 've ever happened if she hadn 't ...
If she hadn 't ...
Why 'd she have so many secrets , Dad ?
Listen , maybe it 's time you came home .
I 'm worried about you , kid . Out here
by yourself . You never see anyone .
The only people you talk to don 't even know your real name .
It 's as if you don 't exist .
That 's the idea . Psychos can 't kill what they can 't find .
Sid , come here .
Mother needs to talk to you .
Everything you touch , Sid , dies .
You 're poison . You 're just like me .
You 're just like me .
Oh , my God . What have they done to me ?
They 'll do it to you .
- They 'll do it to you , baby . - Mum ?
Roman ?
Stab 3 . Jesus , I got to get a new agent .
Someone here ?
Stan , my man . He does good work , huh ?
- Thank you . Thank you very much . - Fuck you very much .
Tyson , go to hell .
Well , excuse us , Sarah . Make-up tests .
Yeah , make-up . You can use it . Damn it , have you seen Roman ?
Look , everyone in the office has gone home already .
- He said it was important . - Everything 's important to Roman .
Oh , shit .
- Director 's office . - Sarah , it 's Roman .
I 'm sorry I 'm running late . I 'm still
on the 405 . I 'm about ten minutes away .
Oh , it 's no problem . I 'm just
looking at your music video awards .
Since I got you on the phone , let 's ...
Let 's talk about your character , okay ?
What character ? I 'm Candy , the chick who gets killed second .
- I 'm only in two scenes . - You 're not happy with your part .
I 'm not happy that I am 35 playing a 21-year-old .
I 'm not happy that I have to die naked .
And I 'm not happy that my character is
too stupid to have a gun in the house ...
after her boyfriend 's been cut into fish sticks .
Great , okay . So let 's ... let 's run the lines .
Fine .
Page 28 . Candy 's big moment .
Page 28 .
Ring-ring . Hello ?
- Hello ? - Who 's this ?
- Who 's this ? - This is Candy .
Hang on . Let me get some clothes .
See ? I don 't understand why I have to start the scene in the shower .
The whole shower thing 's been done . Vertigo . Hello ?
And I mean , my boyfriend just died . Why am I showering ?
Why don 't we just read the scene ?
Candy . Nice name . Is that like Candy Cane or Candy Apple ?
Whatever .
Come on . Who is this ?
I think you have the wrong number .
- But you know my favourite name ? - I 'm hanging up right now .
It 's Sarah .
Roman , that 's not the line .
It is in my script .
Has there been another goddamn rewrite ? How the fuck ...
are we supposed to learn our lines when
there 's a new script every 15 minutes ?
It 's not just a new script . It 's a new movie .
- What ? What movie ? - My movie .
And it 's called Sarah Gets Skewered Like a Fucking Pig .
Still in character , Sarah ?
Shit .
Thank you for calling Sunrise Picture Studios .
If you 'd like today 's commissary menu , press one .
Mr Bridger ?
If you 'd like to hear previews of
upcoming Sunrise Pictures ' releases ...
press four .
If you 'd like information about Sunrise Pictures ' merchandise ...
- Come on . Come on . - Press five .
If you 're trying to reach Lot Security
or you have an emergency , press six .
Shit .
Oh . Fuck .
Look , I wanna get something straight .
I only got into this because the police asked for my help .
Why would the police come to you ?
Well , I did write .
The definitive book on the Woodsboro murders .
I 'm sure you just can 't wait to write another one .
- What about you ? - What about me ?
You said you 'd never leave Woodsboro .
" It 's the only place that 's real . "
But now you 're here . Not with me .
Dewey , I took care of you .
I waited until you were well , but I couldn 't stay there .
It was like dog years . One year in
Woodsboro is like seven anywhere else .
So it 's off to Paris for a week ? New
York for a month ? L.A. forever ?
It was fucking 60 Minutes II .
I couldn 't say no . I could 've been the next Diane Sawyer .
Wait a minute .
What 's wrong with just being Gale Weathers ? I liked her .
It didn 't work , Dewey . We tried . We 're different .
You used to say that was our strength .
Well ...
- Here you go . - Thank you .
Dewey , you 're not just here because
of that second-rate K-Mart ...
straight-to-video version of me , are you ?
Brace yourself , Gale . All of this is actually not about you .
All of what , Dewey ? You do know something , don 't you ?
- Off the record ? - Always .
Two months ago , the Woodsboro police got a call from a woman ...
who said she was with Stab 3 .
She wanted to see the file on Sid , " for research . "
- And ? - The boys said no .
And she wouldn 't give her name .
A month later , the station gets broken into .
- The file room gets ransacked . - And someone stole Sid 's file ?
I already removed it .
I think someone on the film is trying to find Sid .
- I 'm sorry , this is incredible . - I said , " off the record . "
Right .
It 's Jennifer . She needs me .
- Jennifer ? - Gotta run .
Wait . Dewey , where are you going ?
I 'm on duty .
Stop following me .
I happen to be working for the police , damn it .
- You 're not a detective , Gale . - Neither are you , Mr Incognito .
- You left your motor running . - Damn it .
Fans , I can handle . Fans , they want a
picture , they want a conversation .
I can handle fans . You see this , Dewey ?
I haven 't had one of these in a year and
a half . Someone 's going to pay for this .
Jennifer , settle down . What happened ?
- I 'm with him . - You .
Like I 'm ever going to win an award playing you .
- There 's been a second murder . - Who ?
- Sarah Darling . - Where ?
At the studio .
Where ? Nancy Drew wants to know where .
Cotton Weary . Sarah Darling . Don 't you get it ?
Someone 's killing them in the order they die in the movie .
- Dewey , who gets killed third ? - Who gets killed third ?
You do .
I get killed in Stab 3 ? I get killed ?
- Yeah . - Dewey , where are you going ?
I have to get something from my trailer .
Your ... You live here with her ?
- Yeah . - Oh , my God .
I needed a place to stay , and she said she liked having me around .
- Why ? - She says I make her feel safe .
- She says I 'm her rock . - Her rock ?
Yeah . If you weren 't so concerned
with pretensions and appearances ...
you 'd be able to appreciate the
positivity and emotional centredness ...
I provide a woman .
Stone , I 'm headed to the crime scene .
You stay by Jennifer 's side . I suggest a search of the grounds .
Hey , Dewdrop . Can I have a word ?
Just so it can be straight . I 'm the
professional celebrity guard here .
My resume lists Julia Roberts , Salmon Rushdie , Posh Spice .
You are the Hollywood hanger-oner .
Because you 're just no good as a cop any more .
Your resume reads like the obituaries .
So how about you take suggestions from me ? All right ?
Whatever you say .
Same deal ? Found with the body ?
- Yeah , Maureen Prescott again . - This is great .
Ten more murders and we can publish a calendar .
The old " killer playing with the cops " routine .
Very Hannibal Lecter . Very Seven .
Doesn 't the killer come after the cops in those movies ?
Usually one cop makes it .
- And ? - One cop doesn 't .
- Usually . - Detective Kincaid .
- What do we know ? Same killer ? - Hey , hey .
Terminal Entertainment , this is a crime scene , okay ?
Wallace , Miss Weathers is working with me now .
- Thank you , Detective . - You 're welcome .
Well , in that case , I 'm going to go
dust for fingerprints with Jane Pauley .
Photos , Wallace , please ? Thank you .
New pictures , same person . Anything
turn up on your research yet ?
Nothing that will help with these .
What about an increased police presence around Jennifer ?
She 's the next one to get killed in the script .
She has a bodyguard .
And besides , the producers told us that there
were three different versions of the script .
Something about trying to keep the ending
off the Internet . You should know that .
You 're the technical advisor , right ?
Three versions . Three different characters die next .
And we don 't know which one the killer read .
Hey , hold up .
All I ever wanted to do was make a real classic love story .
And the studio said they 'd let me . I just
had to do a scary movie for them first .
And now we 're shut down , and I am fucked .
God , it 's not the end of the world , Roman .
That is so easy for you to say . You
can always go back to , to Must See TV .
You know , I have no movie , I 'm about to turn
30 , and it looks like I 'm now the next target .
- What ? - You ? Why you ?
Do you think this wasn 't a message ?
- Roman Bridger ? - What ?
Mr Bridger , you didn 't tell us ...
you spoke with Sarah Darling before she was murdered .
Spoke with her , when ?
The guard said she was here for a meeting with you .
What meeting ? I don 't ...
We talked with her room-mate too .
Says you called Sarah , told her to come down to the studio .
Room-mate answered the phone . Says it was you .
Wait a minute . No , no .
I never called her . I never told her to go anywhere .
Room-mate says she knows your voice , Mr Bridger .
Well , she wasn 't speaking with me . God .
Look , I did not call Sarah Darling .
Sarah Darling said you did .
Someone 's trying to ruin my movie .
Someone wants to kill my movie .
All right , we 'll talk about your movie down at the station .
All right .
This is the scene where you come with us .
Dewey , Jennifer ... Wait a minute .
She wasn 't talking with me on the phone . I 'm coming .
I 'll call him in . Battery . Mr Riley ,
do you have a cell phone I can borrow ?
Yeah .
- Thank you . - God . Roman .
Remind me not to sleep with him again .
Come here , Cherokee .
California Women 's Crisis Counselling .
My name is Laura . How can I help you ?
Oh , Laura . I do have a crisis .
Okay , well , whatever it is , you can tell me .
Oh , my God . I 've killed someone , Laura .
- Are you sure ? - Huh , I 'm sure .
I killed someone , I know it . Oh , my God .
- Well , then ... - I did .
Then the people you need to call are the police .
No , I need to call you . Just you .
I 'm sorry , your-your voice ...
Don 't you wanna know how you can help , Laura ?
Are you listening to me ? Huh ?
- Who is this ? - It 's Mother , Laura .
Now , be a good girl and turn on the news .
Do as Mother tells you .
You 're not my mother . How did you get this number ? Who is this ?
You know your mother 's voice when you hear it .
Now , turn on the news .
And with a second cast member murdered , Stab 3 ...
has been officially shut down , prompting those involved ...
to hope and pray that these killings maybe over .
Just one question .
Do you think it 's over , Sidney ? Do you ?
The sky was dark this morning
Not a bird in a tree
Is this a wrap party or is this a wrap party ?
Scene 34 . " Maureen 's Murder Flashback . "
I never liked that scene .
That 's because you weren 't in it .
Scenes 40 through 47 .
- " The Prescott House Flashbacks . " - Tom , stop it .
You 're scaring me . Two people are dead .
Scaring you ?
Give the sweet , young ingenue act a rest .
- You 're drunk . - I 'm coping .
I bet she fought and clawed for that Sidney part .
I bet she stepped on any poor girl that got in her way .
So you asked her out and she said no ?
That has nothing to do with it .
Right . Come on , Dewey .
Scene 50 .
" Dewey Saves the Day . "
She 's so focused on success that she never thinks ...
about who she 's hurting to get it .
And you saved her life , like , how many times ?
Gale wants the whole world to love her .
One person 's never enough . She 's a dreamer .
No , she 's a narcissistic , psycho bitch .
No , she 's not .
She 's got a good heart . She does .
She just hides it away because she thinks people see that as weak .
This is a good picture of you . You look just like her .
God , Dewey .
You make it sound like you 're still in love with her .
And I left out the part that she 's cruel ...
and selfish , obsessive and annoying .
We have one Gale Weathers here . We don 't need two .
Hey , Dewdrop , got your girlfriend out here .
Look who I found slinking around the yard . The nightly news .
I wasn 't slinking . I was walking .
You were eaves dropping at the bedroom window .
Yeah , a bedroom that you seemed awfully at home in .
All right , let 's talk .
Come on .
What 's this about , Gale ?
Did you know they released Roman ?
Sarah 's call didn 't come from his cell phone .
Where did it come from then ?
A cloned cell phone . It 's untraceable .
Well , thanks for the update , Gale . Why don 't you just go back home ?
Dewey , wait a minute . Just wait one second .
How old do you think Maureen Prescott is in this picture ?
Nineteen , twenty .
That 's what I thought , so I checked it out .
I cannot find any information about
her at this age . I mean , nothing .
She lived in Woodsboro her whole life .
Someone there must know something .
Almost her whole life . Two years before ...
she met Sidney 's father , she left Woodsboro .
No one has any idea where she went or what she did .
I mean , it 's like she fell into a black hole , Dewey . She vanished .
- So ? - So ?
Why is the killer leaving pictures of-of Maureen ?
And why these pictures at-at ... At that point in her life ?
I don 't know . If I thought like a homicidal maniac ...
then I 'd know how a homicidal maniac thinks .
What ?
- Jennifer . - Jennifer ?
Look at the buildings . The second story . There and there .
It 's the same . It 's the same street 28 years ago .
Oh , my God . Maureen Prescott was at
the back lot at Sunrise Studios .
- Oh , my God . - I got to make some calls .
Steven Stone Protection Services .
Stone , where are you ?
I 'm just checking your tin can , Dewdrop .
Well , come back inside and stay with Jennifer .
Something 's happened . I have to go to the police .
Is that an order , Dewdrop ? Because Steven Stone doesn 't work for you .
Get back in the house , Stone . Would
I call you if it wasn 't important ?
What are you doing in there anyway ?
Me ?
I 'm just checking to make sure there 's no killer in here ...
waiting to off you like he did your little sister .
What did you say ? I can 't believe you said that .
That makes me ...
angry .
Fucker .
Gotta call Kincaid .
Dewey , where is everybody ?
- Oh , God . - Jennifer ?
Angelina ? Tom ?
Oh , my God . What happened ?
Don 't do that . I 'm overreacting .
Dewdrop ?
- Stone ? - Oh , my God .
Oh , God , Stone .
Oh , God .
- Dewey , is he dead ? - Yeah .
Everyone back inside .
It 's all right . Don 't panic .
Okay , outside . Everyone , stay together and try to remain calm .
A phone .
- It 's not mine . - It 's not mine .
Shit . It 's the fax .
" Interior , Jennifer 's house . Living
room , night . " It 's a script page .
What 's it say ?
" With the bodyguard stabbed to death , the five stand trapped .
- He 's rewriting the movie . - As the killer waits outside ...
suddenly the fax machine sends news of their fates . "
It 's a trick . Everybody , outside .
Outside where he can pick us off one by one ?
Shut up .
" The killer prepares to grant mercy to only one of them . "
Don 't you get it ? The killer says he 's
outside because he wants us here inside .
- Which one is it ? - Come on .
" Who will survive ? Is it Jennifer ? Tom ? Angelina ? Dewey ? Gale ?
The killer will give mercy to ... "
Everyone outside .
He grants mercy to who ? I wanna know what happens .
- I wanna know what happens . - Wait for the fucking movie .
I 've got to know . I 'm going back in .
No .
All right , everyone , back . Stay together .
- What 's it say ? - " And the ...
killer will give mercy to ...
- whoever ... " - Whoever ?
Whoever ?
Piece of shit .
" Whoever ... Whoever smells the ... "
I can 't stop rolling down the hill .
Gale . Jennifer .
- Dewey . - Dewey .
Dewey , where are you ?
Over here , Dewey .
- Dewey . - Gale .
Gale , behind you .
Dewey . Are you all right ?
Yeah , never been better .
Yeah , I 'm all right . Where 'd he go ?
- He must 've rolled under the car . - All right , stay close .
Is he back there ?
- No . - No ?
He 's fast . Could 've sworn I hit him .
- Are you all right ? - Yeah .
Thanks for saving me .
Ah , it 's habit .
Oh , God .
What the fuck happened to you ?
- Jennifer , wait a minute . - Who gave you a place to stay ?
Who are you supposed to be protecting ?
Jennifer .
Hey .
My lawyer liked that .
Not as much as I did .
- Angelina ? - Tom was in the house .
How 'd you end up way over there ?
Oh , my God . Tom was in the house .
- Are we safe ? - Safe from who ?
Wait a second .
Another picture .
Whoever it is is now taking credit for Maureen Prescott 's murder .
But we know who killed Maureen
Prescott . Billy Loomis and Stu Macher .
I mean , they even told Sidney how they did it .
Yeah , but if I 'm not mistaken ...
you said in your book that Sidney got it wrong once before .
She accused Cotton Weary of murdering her mother .
And he was sent away for it . Maybe there is a third killer .
Sidney might know something .
I told you . I don 't know where Sidney is .
And even if there was a third killer ,
Sidney doesn 't know about it .
That is for me to decide . I need to talk to her ,
Mr Riley . She is a key element in this case .
I have a press conference in an hour . I need to explain ...
why there are three dead celebrities and a bodyguard .
And a very angry mayor .
Okay , look , we all know this has something to do with Stab 3 .
But what we do not know is why the killer keeps leaving pictures ...
of Maureen Prescott taken over 25 years ago .
And the photographs taken at the same
studio Stab 3 is shooting out of .
What does this have to do with Sid ?
Who knows more about Maureen Prescott than her own daughter ?
Well , Sid 's dad couldn 't help you , and he was married to Maureen .
What 's your problem ?
Last night you were almost charcoal .
You going to help us or what ?
Do you wanna have this conversation with a polygraph ?
Is that a threat , Detective ?
When it 's a threat , you 'll know it .
- Was that a threat ? - Boys , boys .
Why don 't we compare our gun calibres later ?
The issue is Maureen Prescott .
Wrong . The issue is Sidney Prescott .
And either Mr Riley is going to obstruct justice
or he 's going to put me in touch with her .
So , where is she ?
Hi , you 've reached the machine . You can
leave a message . Talk as long as you want .
Sid , it 's me . This is the fifth time I 've called .
Please pick up . I wanna make sure you 're ...
okay .
- Sid . - Dewey .
What are you doing down here ?
Actually , what was I doing up there ?
- Jesus , Dewey . Are you okay ? - Oh , yeah , I 'm all right .
- Is she all right ? - Hey , you know Gale .
It 'd take a direct hit .
So the news said this was the precinct . Who 's this guy Kincaid ?
Come here . I told you to stay hidden .
It 's not safe for you to be here .
The killer called me .
- What ? - Yeah , he found me .
I 'm no more safe there than I am here ,
and at least here I 'm not alone .
Okay , come on .
- Detective Kincaid ? - Yeah .
There 's someone here who wants to help .
Oh , my God . Sidney .
Is the man fast or what ?
- Hi . - Hi , Gale .
- I 'm glad you 're all right . - Thank you .
Sid , this is Detective Kincaid .
Nice to finally meet you , Sidney .
- The killer called her . - What ? When ?
What did he say ?
Oh , you know , the usual small talk .
What 's new ? How you been ? How do you wanna die ?
Sidney , do you have any idea how he could 've gotten your number ?
He could have monitored her calls on a
scanner . Did you call her from the set ?
No .
Do you have her number stored in your memory ?
- Phone memory . - Oh . Yeah , guess I do .
Has anyone else ever used your phone ?
Just Jennifer .
And you .
Hey , I 'm the cop here . You 're in my office , Riley .
The killer leaves a photograph after each murder , Sidney .
They were taken in Hollywood at the same
studio that they 're shooting Stab 3 .
Why didn 't you tell me ? This is my mother , Dewey .
- Why didn 't you say something ? - I was afraid they were bait .
Something to , you know , trick you out of hiding .
Sidney , was she an actress or a model ? Because
they look a lot like publicity stills .
I , don 't know .
Detective , I wanna see this place in the pictures .
- Are you sure ? - Absolutely .
- Slow it down . - Sorry .
Watch the fucking aliens .
I 'm going to go talk to the studio brass about those photos .
Yeah , right . I know where you 're going .
- Yeah , keep an eye on Sidney . - I know where you 're going .
You 're going to get her some flowers and candy , huh ? Huh ?
- Gimme a break . - Yeah , gimme a call .
Just keep your eye on her .
That stairwell over there , that 's
where one of the pictures was taken .
God . I can 't believe she never mentioned any of this .
- She probably just ... - Dewey .
- Sorry . - Martha .
Oh , my God , Sid .
- Hey , hold it right there . Hey . - Don 't shoot .
- I 'm only 17 . - It 's okay . We know her .
We do ?
Tell me that 's his ex-girlfriend , I 'll shoot myself .
It 's Martha Meeks , Randy 's sister .
Randy 's sister ?
- Yeah , can 't you tell ? - We miss you in Woodsboro , guys .
Martha , what are you doing here ?
There 's something you guys should see .
Told ya I 'd make a movie someday . Huh ?
Oh , my God .
Well , if you 're watching this tape ...
it means , as I feared , I did not survive these killings ...
here at Windsor College , and that giving up my virginity to ...
Karen Kolchak at the video store was probably not a good idea .
- Karen Kolchak ? - Yes , Karen Kolchak .
" Creepy Karen " ?
Shut up . She 's a sweet person , okay ?
We were working late . We were putting
away some videos in the porno section ...
and , you know , shit happens .
- Open the door , Randy . - Fifteen minutes .
- It 's my room too . - Paul , 15 minutes .
I 'm leaving my legacy .
Fifteen minutes , Paul . Damn . Anyway ...
the reason I 'm here is to help you so
that my death will not be in vain .
That my life 's work will help save some
other poor soul from getting mutilated .
If this killer does come back and he 's for real ...
there are a few things that you got to remember .
Is this simply another sequel ? Well , if it is , same rules apply .
But here 's the critical thing . If you find yourself dealing ...
with an unexpected back-story and a preponderance ...
of exposition , then the sequel rules do not apply .
Because you 're not dealing with the
sequel . You are dealing with ...
the concluding chapter of a trilogy .
Trilogy .
That 's right . It 's a rarity in the horror field ...
but it does exist , and it is a force to be reckoned with .
Because true trilogies are all about
going back to the beginning ...
and discovering something that wasn 't true from the get-go .
Godfather , Jedi , all revealed something ...
that we thought was true that wasn 't true .
So if it is a trilogy you are dealing with ...
here are some super trilogy rules .
One : You 've got a killer who 's going to be superhuman .
Stabbing him won 't work . Shooting him won 't work .
Basically , in the third one , you 've got
to cryogenically freeze his head ...
decapitate him or blow him up .
Number two : Anyone , including the main character , can die .
This means you , Sid . I 'm sorry . It 's the final chapter .
It could be fucking Reservoir Dogs by the time this thing is through .
Number three : The past will come back to bite you in the ass .
Whatever you think you know about the past , forget it .
The past is not at rest . Any sins you think ...
were committed in the past are about
to break out and destroy you .
So in closing , let me say ...
good luck , Godspeed ...
and for some of you , I 'll see you soon .
Because the rules say some of you ain 't going to make it . I didn 't .
Not if you 're watching this tape .
Thank you . And you be careful . Say hi to your folks for me .
You be careful too , Sid .
- Bye , Dewey . Come visit us soon . - I will , Martha .
- Thank you . - Bye .
I 've got an idea . I 'll hook up with you guys later .
- Do you want us to come with you ? - I work better alone .
Why don 't you try to figure out where
those other pictures were taken .
- I can see nothing 's changed . - No .
Oh , shit .
Hello .
- Jeez . - What the hell are you doing ?
Being Gale Weathers . What the hell are you doing ?
- I am Gale Weathers . - Here 's how I see it .
I 've got no house , no bodyguard , no movie , and I 'm being stalked .
Because someone wants to kill me ? No ,
because someone wants to kill you .
So now , starting now , I go where you go .
That way , if someone wants to kill me , I 'll be with you .
And since they really want to kill you ,
they won 't kill me , they 'll kill you .
- Make sense ? - None .
You know , in the movies , I play you as being much smarter .
And as a sane person . For you , that must be quite a stretch .
That 's funny .
- Need to get in that building ? - Yeah .
Is there a story in that building ?
Maybe .
Gale Weathers would find a way .
Bitch . All right , wait . Just ...
Don 't tell me what to do .
Basements , wow .
Basements creep me out .
You 'd make a fascinating interview .
Hello ?
Hi . Excuse me . I am Gale Weathers ...
and I 'm here researching with the police this photo .
It was taken at the studio . Her name is Maureen Prescott .
Back then it was probably Roberts .
- Hey , are you ... - No .
- But you look just ... - Like her ?
I 've been hearing it all my life .
It 's uncanny .
I was up for Princess Leia . I was this close .
So , who gets it ? The one who sleeps with George Lucas .
I 'm sorry . I didn 't mean to bring up a sore subject for you .
Sure , you didn 't . None of them did .
So , how can I help you ? Or do you want
me to tell you who you look like ?
How about some information on Maureen Roberts ?
I don 't work for the cops , sweetie . I work for the studio .
Really ? Well , would you work for ...
the president ?
The president of the studio .
Fifty dollars ? Who are you ? A reporter for Woodsboro High ?
It 's worth two grand .
Are you going to help Gale Weathers or not ?
I know every face in here .
I got a respect for the unknown actor .
If they 're looking for Maureen Roberts ,
they 're never going to find her .
Rina Reynolds they will .
Rina Reynolds . Stage name .
You should talk , Judy Jurgenstern .
What are these movies ? Amazombies , Space Psycho ...
Creatures from the San Andreas Fault .
Horror pictures back in Milton 's heyday .
- Back in what ? - Back in what ?
John Milton .
The horror producer ? Those were his movies .
Come on , Sid .
Oh , my God . Sidney Prescott .
Oh , my God . I 'm Angelina Tyler . I 'm you . I mean , I 'm not .
I mean , I was .
I thought ... Well , if there 's no movie ...
then no one would care if I took some souvenirs .
Souvenirs ?
I may never win another role , so these may be ...
my only memories , you know , of Hollywood .
I know it 's weird because it 's your life and all , but ...
I wanted to make you proud , Sidney .
Oh . Well , I 'm sure I would 've been .
The real Sidney . The real person .
I wish ...
I wish it would 've worked out .
Hey ...
Angelina ?
Hello ?
Close call .
What are you doing here ?
It occurred to me that I 've never snuck through your bedroom window .
See what you do to me ?
What have I done to you ?
About the , sex stuff ?
You know , I 'm not trying to rush you at all .
Would you settle for a PG-13 relationship ?
Dewey .
Sidney , I 'm in here .
Over here .
Yes . Mother will protect you from the bogeyman .
Come into the bedroom .
Hide in Mummy 's bed .
I lied , Sidney .
I can 't protect you at all .
You don 't deserve to be protected . You didn 't protect me .
We did your mum a favour , Sid . That woman was a slutbag whore ...
who flashed her shit all over town like she was Sharon Stone .
Because let 's face it , Sidney , your mother was no Sharon Stone .
Sidney 's mother was fucking my father .
Sid , where are you ?
Dewey . Dewey , help me .
Sidney ? Give Mummy a kiss and we 'll make up .
- No . - Sidney .
Sid .
Sid , are you okay ? What happened ?
The killer 's in the house , Dewey . He 's upstairs .
- And my mother ... - Let 's go , let 's go .
I heard her voice . I saw her , Dewey .
- Upstairs . Come on , let 's go . - It 's okay , Sid .
You weren 't supposed to go in that house .
It 's all set up for the murder scene .
- I 'm sorry you had to see that . - He was in there , Dewey .
He was in there , I swear , I swear .
You know I believe you .
- What happened ? - Kincaid , hey .
There 's nobody up here .
Come on .
- Come on . - Okay , so I stole the mask .
Whatever . I didn 't know you got the gas chamber for that .
- You stole the mask ? - I took it .
You took the mask or you stole the mask ?
I took it as like a souvenir .
Don 't look at me . I didn 't take shit .
I know he was there .
I am not dreaming , I am not crazy .
- He was there in Woodsboro . - That 's not Woodsboro , Sidney .
You know what I mean . But he was there .
He or she , or whoever this is .
We 're going to take you back to the station , keep you under watch .
Put you in a safe house . Whatever it takes .
Come on .
It 's all right , Sid . We all believe you .
- He 's watching . - And he wants you .
Hey , Dew .
- Dew . - Come on .
- We have to go catch up with Sid . - Take a look at this first .
- Someone we know ? - Where 'd you get this ?
We got it . Archives .
Sidney 's mother was an actress . Three movies .
Horror movies .
Wanna know who produced all three ?
Who ?
- There 'll be other movies , Roman . - Not only did they ...
Did they kill the film , but they killed my cast .
Now , nobody 's going to wanna work
with me . Variety called me a pariah .
I don 't even know what a pariah is . Why-Why
couldn 't someone have killed the cast from Stab 1 ?
Huh ? Or Stab 2 ? Why me ? What ... John , what did we do wrong ?
Hollywood is full of criminals whose careers are flourishing .
I 'm not a criminal . I was questioned .
Yeah , but that 's all . I was questioned . That 's it .
That 's good for your mystique .
You think it will help me get work ?
Roman . John .
Jennifer , and guests . To what do I owe the honour ?
Rina Reynolds .
Rina Reynolds ? Who 's Rina Reynolds ?
Why don 't you head to the house ? Tell
everybody not to cut the cake without me .
Oh , God , I forgot . Your birthday .
Yeah .
Happy birthday , Roman .
Yeah , as if life isn 't tragic enough .
Shut the doors behind you , please .
So , you knew Sidney Prescott 's mother .
- Who ? - Rina Reynolds ?
Do you know how many actors have
worked for me ? Hundreds . Thousands .
- He didn 't say she was an actor . - Good catch .
- So what 's the point ? - No point .
I 'm just going to give , Detective Kincaid a call .
I remember . She was a bit player in a couple of my movies .
A nobody . So what does it matter ?
Oh , come on .
You have made millions off the story of her murder .
You 're obsessed with her , and you 're obsessed with her daughter .
All right , easy , Geraldo . Why don 't you tell us the truth ?
What the hell are you guys getting at ?
I make horror films , that 's what I do .
The studio came to me with Stab .
They came to me . Check it out .
- But you knew who she was . - When we did the first Stab ...
I realised I had known Maureen Prescott before .
I mean , as Rina .
I couldn 't tell anyone . Can you imagine the press ?
And now ? I mean , murders on your set .
- And-And still you say nothing ? - Get real .
- That would make me a suspect . - Just because you knew her ?
- Yeah . - I don 't think so .
Just what did happen to Maureen when she was in Hollywood ?
Now , you listen to me , Lois Lane . Let it go . It 's dead and buried .
How would you like to see it dug up on national TV ?
Why don 't you tell me what happened ?
It was in the ' 70s . Everything was different .
I was well-known for my parties . Rina knew what they were .
It was for girls like her to meet men .
Men who could get them parts ...
if they made the right impression .
Nothing happened to her that she didn 't invite ...
in one way or another no matter what she said afterwards .
Are you saying she ...
I 'm saying things got out of hand .
Maybe they did take advantage of her .
You know , Maybe the sad truth is ...
this is not the city for innocents .
No charges were brought . And the bottom line is ...
Rina Reynolds wouldn 't play by the rules .
You wanna get ahead in Hollywood ?
You got to play the game , or go home .
What do you know about trilogies ?
You mean , like movie trilogies ?
You seem to like movies , Detective .
Call me Mark , would you ? Because I 'm
going to keep calling you Sidney .
I 'll call you Mark when you catch the killer , Detective .
All I know about movie trilogies is that in the third one ...
all bets are off .
- Did you request this case ? - No . They tend to put me ...
on the ones that deal with the business .
I grew up here , and I know my way around the studios .
Huh .
Must be exciting . Beautiful place , beautiful people .
To me , Hollywood is about death .
Excuse me ?
I 'm a homicide detective , remember ?
And when you see what I see day in and day out ...
the violence that people do to each other ...
you get haunted .
I think you know about that .
What do you mean ?
I know what it 's like to see ghosts that don 't go away .
To be watching a scary movie in your
head , whether you want to or not .
Watching it alone .
Ghosts are tough . You can 't shoot ghosts .
Can 't arrest ghosts .
But the best way to stop being haunted is to be with people .
You 're here , you 're not hiding .
You 've done the right thing , Miss Prescott .
What did you know about your mother ?
I always thought I had the perfect mum .
Perfect family .
Till I found out I was wrong . She ...
She had a secret life , and I tried to understand that , and ...
soon as I thought that I had , more secrets .
I don 't know who my mum was .
You know who she was to you .
Here 's the deal . I 'm off to search the set .
I think what you saw is real . That 's the good news .
- How is that good news ? - Because that means ...
that we 're dealing with an ordinary flesh-and-blood killer .
And I know how to handle guys like that .
Oh , yeah ? How ?
Catch him or kill him .
Hey , Detective .
What 's your favourite scary movie ?
My life .
Mine too .
We have to think . Strategise .
Milton 's the key to everything .
He 's a pervert , he 's not a killer .
He 's got to be involved somehow . We should follow him .
We 're going to go back to the precinct and
we 're going to tell Kincaid and Sidney ...
what we found out .
My Gale would be much more aggressive .
My Gale would suspect everybody .
My Gale would ...
- Shut up . - Shut up .
Riley here .
- Dewey , it 's Sidney . - Hey , Sid .
I 'm with Gale . We 're on our way to see you .
No .
Listen , I 'm not at the station . John Milton
called me and said he had something to tell me .
Something about my mum . I 'm going to meet him at his house .
Wait , Sid , I 'm not so sure that 's a good idea .
It 's okay . Kincaid 's with me . I 've got official big-time ...
L.A.P.D. protection , but I 'd feel better if you were there .
We 're on our way , but still , Sid ...
Thanks .
What ?
Looks like we 're going to that party after all .
Hey , guys . Come on in . Join the party .
Yeah , well , actually , we 're here to see Sidney .
- Really ? Sidney 's here . - Where ?
- Where 's Sidney ? - She 's right there .
Jesus . Not " Sidney , " Sidney .
- Like I 'm " Gale " and she 's Gale . - Sidney Prescott ?
- Yeah . - No , I 'd never invite her here .
- She 's on her way . - Well , the more the merrier .
God , this house is incredible .
It 's old Hollywood .
Yeah . Could the dude have more money ?
Supposedly , Milton has a secret screening room ...
that was like the scene back in the ' 70s , you know .
It was , like , drinks and drugs and girls and movies and shit .
Wow . Wish I could 've seen it .
Big old screening room shouldn 't be too hard to find .
I 'm going to go ... I 'm going to go check this place out .
Whoa , whoa , whoa . Just one damn minute .
There 's a psycho killer on the loose .
And you want to go traipsing around this gigantic mansion ?
Have you ever actually seen the Stab movies ? Every time ...
this dude enters a room , he ends up a goddamn shish kebab .
I 'll go with you , Roman .
There you go . You guys wanna come ?
It 'll be okay . We 're going to stick together .
You 're not sticking . Wait up .
We 're going to stay here and wait for Sid .
We 'll be right back .
If you were a screening room ...
where would you be ?
I bet in the basement .
I don 't like basements .
Ooh , it 's spooky .
- Ooh , Weredad . - Damn , it 's dark in here .
I loved that movie .
Forget the movie . What if Milton 's crazy ...
and he 's going to jump out of his screening
room with a sling blade or something ?
- He won 't . - You sure about that ?
- What 's down there ? - Zombies and aliens .
You know , what you look like without make-up , Jennifer .
Jesus . Stop pretending I wasn 't the best you 've ever had .
Oh , stop pretending I even remember .
Stop pretending .
Roman ?
- Any sign of her ? - No .
This is so strange .
It sure is .
Dewey , do you have caller ID on your cell phone ?
Yeah .
All right , use it and press " send . "
What the hell ?
What is this thing ?
Is this what he ... What the hell ?
Dewey , he 's got our voices .
He 's got Sid .
He 's got us all .
- Oh , my God . We got to find her . - Come on .
All right , take the gun .
Go find Roman and Jennifer . I 'm going to get the others .
- Be careful . - You too .
Tyson . Angelina . You up there ?
- Roman . - Tyson .
Angelina .
Damn it .
Okay , come on . We got to get out of here .
- Where 's Angelina ? - I don 't know . She went in here .
I came in after her . Now she 's gone .
- Great . - What 's wrong ?
Looks like Stab 3 is back in production .
Roman .
Jennifer .
Roman ?
- Is he dead ? - Yeah , very .
Dewey . Dewey .
Dewey ?
Dewey .
God , I 'm sorry . Jennifer , Gale , look .
- I found a secret passage . - Roman 's dead .
- What ? - The killer 's here .
- What ? - Come on .
Let go of me . I 'm getting out of here .
You 're not safe alone .
Listen to me .
I did not fuck that pig Milton to get a leading role ...
just to die here with second-rate celebrities like you two .
- Gale . I 'm up here . - Come on .
- Dewey . - You guys should get out too .
It 's crazy to still be here .
- Wait . - Come on .
- Dewey . - Gale , Jennifer , up here .
Dewey , here . He got Roman and Angelina too .
We 'll be safer if we stick together , won 't we ?
Of course . Why ...
What 's going on ? Oh , shit .
- Hey . - Dewey .
Dewey .
No .
Help . Police . Help . Help .
Police . Help .
Oh , you motherfucker .
Damn .
Dewey . Dewey .
Behind the mirror , Dewey .
Gale . Get away . Dewey .
- Do you hear something ? - Get away from me , you asshole .
Get away from me . You don 't scare me .
Look , Gale . The mirror 's moving .
- Gale . Gale . - Stand back , Gale .
You can 't kill me . I 'm the killer in Stab 3 . I 'm the killer .
Gale , cover .
Dewey .
- Tyson . - Tyson .
I 'm going to check down here . You call for help .
Okay .
Tyson .
- Tyson ? - Any sign of him ?
No .
All right . I 'm going to check out front .
Dew ...
Gale .
- Dewey ? - Gale .
- Who is this ? - Dewey , it 's me .
Gale , where are you ?
I 'm in the basement . I 'm trapped .
- Where ? - There 's a door in the kitchen .
Hurry .
Wait . How do I know this is you , Gale , and not the killer ?
Dewey , open the fucking door . It 's me .
Well , don 't you think that 's what the killer would say ?
Come on . He 's out cold at the bottom of the stairs .
Hey .
Dewey . Dewey .
All right , all right . It 's pizza , not a party .
Everybody get back to work . Anybody seen my fucking partner ?
Hey , Morgan , what did you pay ?
- Hello ? - Hello ?
- Who is this ? - Who is this ?
- Who 's calling ? - Who 's calling ?
Gale , Dewey , whoever , call me back . I can only hear myself .
I only hear you too , Sidney .
- Who is this ? - The question isn 't who I am .
The question is : Who 's with me ?
- Sidney , stay away . - Sidney .
Don 't do it . If you do one thing to
attract attention to yourself ...
one thing , I 'll kill them both .
Now , do you have somewhere we can be alone ?
- Yes . - Yeah . Go there .
Oh , it 's hard being friends with you , Sidney .
When you 're friends with Sidney , you die .
Well , these friends don 't have to , Sidney . It 's up to you .
How do I know their voices are ...
Are real ?
How do you know you 're not hearing things ?
How do you know I 'm not someone in your head ? Somewhere you know .
- Don 't come here , Sidney . - Dewey .
- Or do you ? - You 're dead .
I don 't want them . I want you .
It 's simple . You show yourself , they survive .
- You run , they die . - Oh , God .
Don 't you wanna know , Sidney , who killed her ?
Don 't you wanna know who killed your mother ?
- Have you seen Kincaid ? - Yeah , I saw him go out .
Wallace is still looking for him .
Where ?
She 'd have been so happy , Sidney , to know we 'd be together .
I 'll call you when you 're on your way .
Shit . Shit . Shit .
Holy shit .
What ?
You follow directions well , Sidney .
Now , welcome to the final act .
See that metal detector ?
Use it .
All over , Sidney . Everywhere .
Everywhere . The other leg too .
Show it to me .
Throw it in the pool .
Now , come inside , Sidney .
No fucking way . How do I know they 're not dead already ?
They 're right inside , waiting for you .
Look for yourself .
Now that we 're all here , the party can begin .
- Dewey . - Sid .
- Where is he ? - I don 't know .
He 's right there .
Oh , shit .
Think again .
It 's your turn to scream , asshole .
Yeah .
It 's okay . Just give me a second .
Okay .
- Hurry , Sid . - Sidney ? Sidney ?
Where is he ?
Be careful .
I heard shots . Tyson 's dead . What 's going on ?
- What 're you doing here , Kincaid ? - Looking for you .
Tyson said there was a party here tonight , and I thought , oh .
Third act celebration . Thought I better check it out .
Alone ? Where 's your partner ?
Hey , Miss Prescott .
I 'm here to help . Put the gun down .
Put the gun down .
No .
Sid . Wake up , Sid . Sid , come on .
- Wake up . - Sidney .
Sid , shoot him . Sid .
Shoot the fucker .
Shoot him .
You want me , motherfucker ? Come and get me .
Run .
Sid .
Come in here , please .
It 's just me , Sid .
Oh , I was so pretty .
Everybody loved me .
Have you missed me , Sidney ?
Would you like to hold me one last time ?
What 's the matter ? What are you staring at ?
Don 't you remember your mother ?
You 're not going anywhere , Sidney .
It 's time you came to terms with me and with Mother .
Maybe you never knew her at all , Sidney .
Maybe you just can 't get past the surface of things .
- Who the hell are you ? - The other half of you .
I searched for a mother too , an actress named Rina Reynolds .
Tried to find her my whole life .
And four years ago , I actually tracked her down .
Knocked at her door , thinking she 'd welcome me with open arms .
But she had a new life and a new name : Maureen Prescott .
You were the only child she claimed , Sidney .
She shut me out in the cold forever .
Her own son .
Roman Bridger , director . And brother .
She slammed the door in my face , Sid .
She said I was Rina 's child ...
and Rina was dead .
And it struck me .
What a good idea . So I watched her .
I made a little home movie . A little-little family film .
It seems Maureen ... Mum ...
She really got around . I mean , Cotton was one thing .
Everybody knew about that .
But Billy 's father ? That was the key .
Your boyfriend didn 't like seeing his daddy in my film too much .
He didn 't like it at all .
But once I supplied the motivation , all
the kid needed was a few pointers .
Have a partner to sell out in case you
get caught , find someone to frame .
It was like he was making a movie .
You . This is all because of you .
I 'm a director , Sid .
- I direct . - Oh .
I had no idea that they were going to make a film of their own .
Oh , shit .
What a film it turned out to be , huh ?
I mean , introducing Sidney , the victim .
Sidney , the survivor . Sidney , the star .
All right . You 're going to be all right . Just apply pressure .
Here , take this . Get the son of a bitch .
Let 's go .
Fine , you got what you wanted , hero and villain face-to-face .
Well , you know what happens now ? The villain dies .
Exactly .
But I 'm not the villain , Sid . You are .
Here he is , the man who gave away your mother 's innocence .
Huh ? What he did to her made her a slut .
Didn 't it ? Huh ? She never recovered from
that night , right here in this room .
They fucked her three ways from Sunday . Ruined her life .
Ruined yours too , didn 't it , Sid ?
You hate him , Sid ?
Come on , I know you do . I 'm sure you do .
I know who you are . I know what happened to my mother .
And I want you to understand , I 'm going to make you pay .
That 's what the police are going to
find on Milton 's answering machine ...
right next to his lifeless , mutilated corpse .
What ? Can 't hear ya .
You don 't have to do this , Roman .
Just tell me what you want . I can make it happen .
Any picture . Name your budget . Script approval .
- Final cut . - I already have it .
No .
God . You spineless bastard .
No , Sid , that would be you . You did it all .
You did it , you called them all . Even your closest friends .
Living in total isolation , the
pressure of another movie about you ...
the discovery that Milton destroyed Mummy dearest ...
you finally just snapped .
One , two , three .
And who 's our hero , huh ? The sole survivor . Who 's the one ...
who bravely faced down the psychopath
and killed her with her own knife ?
You 're going to pay for the life you stole from me , Sid .
For the mother , and for the family , and for the stardom and ...
Goddamn it . Everything you have that should 've been mine .
God . Why don 't you stop your whining and get
on with it ? I 've heard this shit before .
Stop .
You know why you kill people , Roman ? Do you ?
I don 't wanna hear it .
Because you choose to . There is no one else to blame .
Stop it . Fucking damn it .
Why don 't you take some fucking responsibility ?
- Fuck you . - Fuck you .
Sid ? Sidney ?
Sidney ?
Sidney .
Leave her alone .
Dewey , do something .
- Stand back . - Dewey .
Sid . Sid .
Sid ?
Where is he ?
Hey . Lose something ?
Found something .
There 's got to be another way in there . Come on .
You hurt her , I swear I 'll kill you .
Dewey .
Down this way . There 's another hallway .
There 's another door down here .
- This thing 's not budging . - Look around for something heavy .
- Go that way . - Okay .
I shot you .
I guess we think alike .
Mother 's dead .
And there is nothing you can do about that .
I still got to make my movie .
Stab 3 , right ?
Kincaid , hang in there .
Roman ? It was Roman ?
Be careful , Sid . Randy said the killer 's always superhuman .
Yeah , well , he wasn 't superhuman , Dewey .
He wasn 't superhuman at all .
- You can 't fucking kill me . - Head .
- Head . Head , Dewey . - What ?
Head . Shoot him in the head .
Thanks .
No problem .
Look .
Come on , Cherokee . Come on .
- Yeah , she 's doing great . - Yeah .
Look .
What are you doing with that ?
Will you sign it for me , Gale ?
You hate that book .
Besides , I 'm done with that kind of reporting .
For me . Will you sign it for me ?
You 're a nut .
Okay .
- Will you ? - Dewey .
I know it 'll never work , and you know it 'll never work .
But what I 'm asking is just to see if we 're wrong .
We don 't know everything , Gale .
I mean , you think you do , but ...
You 're a brave man , Dewey Riley .
I 'm really scared right now .
Inside .
Sid , we 've been waiting for you . We 're going to start a movie .
- What kind of movie ? - You have to come and see .
♪ Take a little walk to the edge of town ♪
♪ Now , spread your wings and fly ♪
♪ Don 't the lights of the city look so damn pretty ♪
♪ When you 're flying so high ♪
♪ It 's hard to know about there down below ♪
♪ The streets fade they 're swimming deep in blood ♪
♪ It seems to make me groan and cry ♪
♪ You really wanna know what 's wrong with this land ♪
♪ Just scratch your head with your red right hand ♪
♪ I 'm talking about blood , babe ♪
♪ It 's in your veins ♪
♪ Your mummy and daddy ♪
♪ They 've got the same ♪
♪ You 're under the mirror day after day ♪
♪ You see a pretty face crumbling away ♪
♪ As you become your mum and daddy ♪
♪ Scream once , scream twice now scream again ♪
♪ Cover that face with your red right hand ♪
♪ So , is this the end ♪
♪ For us , my friend ♪
♪ Well as though we rise ♪
♪ As the day breaks the dawn ♪
♪ And as the moon hides the sun ♪
♪ Oh , the sun ♪
♪ No more sorrow ♪
♪ All those crying days are gone ♪
♪ Now it 's gone ♪
♪ So , is this the end ♪
♪ For us , my friend ♪
♪ Spoke to my God today asked him why he 'd gone away ♪
♪ Hitched on a rocket ride into the sun ♪
♪ Said , son I got one for ya down there in California ♪
♪ Just take a look around at all you 've done ♪
♪ You 're automatic like a burning gun ♪
♪ You 're a star like everyone ♪
♪ Talked to my soul today couldn 't keep my brain away ♪
♪ So I found a holiday behind the sun ♪
♪ Took all the friends I could spun out in Hollywood ♪
♪ Hit up on a climate everyone ♪
♪ You 're automatic like a burning gun ♪
♪ You 're a star like everyone ♪
♪ You could save the world ♪
♪ Could be shining on my pearl ♪
♪ Just might find your way my pearl ♪
♪ Shine ♪
♪ You 're automatic like a burning gun ♪
♪ You 're a star like everyone ♪
♪ You could save the world ♪
♪ Could be shining on my pearl ♪
♪ Just might find your way my pearl ♪
♪ Shine ♪